Guide to the Daylight Books Records, 2004-2019 RL.10192
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Daylight Books records
2004-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Daylight Community Arts Foundation
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
RL.10192
10 Linear Feet
Daylight is a nonprofit organization dedicated to publishing art and photography books. It was founded by Michael Itkoff and Taj Forer in 2004. This collection includes materials, largely page proofs and galleys, from the publication of several Daylight books. There is also assorted loose materials promoting and publicizing Daylight's publications.
Historical note
Daylight Community Arts Foundation was founded by Michael Itkoff and Taj Forer while they were students at Sarah Lawrence College in 2004. Along with sponsoring photography projects and community events, the organization publishes Daylight Magazine and operates Daylight Books, which publishes documentary photography books.
Provenance
The Daylight Books Records were received as a gift by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from 2015 to 2019.
Separated Materials
Published versions of books and Daylight Magazine have been separated for individual cataloging. Separately cataloged titles can be found in the Duke Libraries Catalog.
Collection Overview
The majority of this collection consists of proofs and galleys created during the process of publishing documentary photography books. Materials have been arranged by title. Many photograph proofs include edits and markups regarding the color and printing process. Also included is a small amount of miscellaneous material promoting and publicizing the work of Daylight.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Publishers and publishing; Documentary photography; Daylight Books; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Publications, 2004-2018
  - After Hiroshima, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - As Is, 2018 (Box 14)
    Scope and Contents
    Photobook maquette
  - As Is, 2018 (Box 14)
    Page proofs
  - Bull City Summer, 2014; 2 folders (Box 3, Box 10)
    Page proofs with edits and markups; dust jacket cover; book review.
  - Coming of Age in Wonderland: Portraits of Teenage Bermuda, 2017 (Box 12)
    Photograph page proofs
  - The Day the Dam Collapses, 2013 (Box 1)
    Thumbnail printouts of images.
  - Dread and Dreams, 2015 (Box 3)
    Book boards.
  - Empire, 2013 (Box 1, Box 10)
    Page proofs with markups and edits; dummy sample book (blank).
  - First Fleet, 2018 (Box 15)
  - Floating Island, 2013 (Box 4)
    Page proofs (2 sets) with edits and markups.
  - The Forbidden Reel, 2013 (Box 4, Box 11)
    Page proofs with edits and markups; cover boards; dummy sample book (blank).
  - Gays in the Military, 2014; 4 folders (Box 2, Box 10)
  - Ground: A Reprise of Photographs from the Farm Security Administration, 2015 (Box 7)
    Maquette.
  - Growing up in the New Age, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 2, Oversize-folder 1)
  - A Handful of Dust, 2017 (Box 15)
  - Homeplace, 2013 (Box 1)
    Page proofs with markups and edits.
  - The Last Roll, undated (Box 1)
    Unbound pages.
  - May the Road Rise to Meet You, 2013 (Box 10)
    Exhibition proposal
  - Minescape, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Once Upon a Time in Almeria, 2017; 3 folders (Box 13)
    Proof papers
  - Orgasm, undated (Box 1)
    Page printouts with markups and edits.
  - Photographs by Iraqi Civilians, 2004, 2010-2013; 7 folders (Box 10, Box 14)
    Exhibit coverage; References to the project in Fred Ritchin's Bending the Frame and Susie Linfield's The Cruel Radiance; snapshots, proofs, dummy sample books.
  - The Photographs Not Taken, 2012 (Box 10)
    Reviews of book.
  - The Pines, 2017 (Box 12)
    Book proof
  - Real Pictures, 2018 (Box 14)
  - Los Restos de la Revolucion, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 1, Oversize-folder 1, Box 10)
  - The Return, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Box 7, Box 10)
    Page proofs with markups and edits; cover boards; 2 maquettes; review of book.
  - Rockabye, 2015 (Box 2)
  - Sandy, 2015 (Box 10)
    Review of book.
  - Skaters, 2017 (Box 13)
  - The Superlative Light, 2014 (Box 1)
    Page proofs with edits and markups; cover proofs.
  - Tiger Legacy: Stories of Massillon Football, 2015 (Box 7)
  - TransCuba, 2013 (Box 4, Box 5, Folder 1, Box 10)
    Page proofs with markups and edits; cover boards; dummy sample book (blank).
  - Upstate, 2018 (Box 14)
  - We Were There: Austin Concert Crowds, Shot from the Pit 2007-2017 (Box 12)
  - Wild and Precious, 2015 (Box 1)
  - Daylight Magazine, 2004-2007; 4 folders (Box 2, Box 5, Folder 3, Box 10, Box 14)
    Proofs for issues 3 and 6; press coverage of magazine.
  - Gilad Ophir, Untitled from the series Necropolis, 1997 (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous Materials
  - Coverage and news clippings about of Daylight, 1970-2018 (Box 2, Box 14)
  - Promotional materials, 2004-2019 (Box 2, Box 6, Box 10, Box 12, Box 14, Box 15)
  - Daylight Community Arts Foundation, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Photograph of co-founders Michael Itkoff and Taj Forer, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Daylight Photo Awards banners (4 banners), 2010-2012 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Distributed Art Publishers catalogs, 2012-2015; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Next Of Kin (NOK) exhibit pamphlet created by Inbal Abergil, 2016 (Box 6)
  - Postcards/notes from photographers, 2015 and undated (Box 6)
  - Paper sample book, undated (Box 7)
  - "Indefinitely" exhibition prints by Katlin Koenning, undated; 21 items 21 color prints (11 x 14 inches) in 1 box. (Box 8)
  - Consortium Book Sales and Distribution catalogs, 2016 (Box 10)
  - In Passing: A Book About Death, edited by Todd Herman, 2005 (Box 10)
    With blurb by Taj Forer.
  - Evangeline: Photographs by Mark Marchesi (prospectus), undated (Box 10)
  - Recently: Photographs by Elaine Mayes, 2013 (Box 12)
    Artist's Edition, Copy 2. Inscribed to Daylight by artist Elaine Mayes.
  - Assorted correspondence, 2015 (Box 10)
  - Floorplan of Hillsborough, N.C. offices, undated (Box 11)
  - Assorted correspondence and papers, 2005-2006 (Box 14)
  - Assorted snapshots, undated (Box 14)
  - La Boquilla project, 2005-2006 (Box 14)
  - Lake Lacawac, 1988-2006 (Box 14)
  - Moving walls exhibit 13 submissions: Akwesasne Mohawk Reservation, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Non-profit status, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Carabanchel by Mark Parasandolo, 2014 (Box 14)
  - Serenissima: Venice in Winter by Frank Van Riper and Judith Goodman, 2016 (Volume 1)